RUNNING PATCHED VERSION

[LiveRAGManager] Query: ''
Principles of Business Management https://www.kdpublications.in ISBN: 978-81-968394 -3-7 1 Unit 1 Unit 1: Introduction Concepts , Objectives , Nature Scope and Significance of Management Evolution of Management Thought -Contribution Taylor , Weber and Fayol Management 1.1 Essentials of Management: Introduction: "Management" is a broad idea that touches every aspect of our lives. Various levels, including individual, group, regional, national, and worldwide, can be involved. Even on a more individual level, we can perceive the relevance of this broad idea. Take the case of a student who successfully controls his or her studies by c reating a schedule, sorting books and other resources, setting goals, monitoring progress, and passing or receiving the highest possible grade. Similarly, at the family level, parents are in charge of all matters pertaining to their children's education, household budgeting, and future planning. At the elementary level, we observe that the principal, with the help of the teachers, oversees the whole school's disciplinary measures, as well as the students' work and academic achievement. Therefore, as we have seen, management is an integral aspect of our everyday lives. Everyone works in a group, and every group has its own set of objectives, and management is the key to reaching those objectives. The administration of any given group ùbe it a family, a government, an army, a corporation, a cricket team, a school, etc. ùis essential to the attainment of its social and economic objectives. In short, management is the art and science of getting things done by making the most of available resources (both human and material) via careful preparation, execution, and evaluation of plans and strategies. A more technical definition of management would include the six Ms: people, money, machines, materials, methods, and markets. With the guidance of upper management, these assets are put to good use so that the company may accomplish its goals, which may in clude increasing sales and profits, expanding into new markets, developing and releasing innovative goods, and so on. There are many different notions that can be used to illustrate what management is and what it encompasses.
